

Marcos Porto

Front-end Engineer





About Me

Hello! I'm Marcos 🖖 I worked for about 8 years as a Production Engineer in business administration, however, currently I've been dedicating myself to completing the career transition to software development. As a result, I've reached great front-end skills and lately on Ruby on Rails, which I'm really enjoying. Finally, I'm a person motivated by new challenges, able to work autonomously, and quickly grasp new concepts.

Age

33

mrcsporto@gmail.com

Whatsapp Address

Email

Fortaleza, Ceará, Brazil

+55 (85) 99752-3466

Professional Skills

HTML Ruby CSS Postgres Git/Github JavaScript

Portfolio

Mass Orders Upload to Batabase

Application to register client orders by upon .csv file.

Ruby

Tic-Tac-Toe Game

Tic-tac-toe multiplayer game

Javascript

Inventory Control System

Public REST API to manage products, inventory centers and orders.

Ruby

Landing Page

Institutional Landing Page

CSS

Reporting Control System

Application and also an API for reporting abductions in an apocalypse world.

Ruby

Institutional Company Website

Etiquetas Fortaleza Website

CSS

See More →

Work Experience

Procurement Buyer at Gocase

Apr 2020 - Nov 2022

I started the purchasing department. From hiring people, standardizing processes, developing KPIs, and also managing OKRs.

Process Engineer at Bosch Portugal

Apr 2019 - Apr 2020

I was responsible to optimize the manufacturing processes, manage production capacity, line balancing and also build dashboards in Power BI.

Operation Manager at Normatel Home Center

Apr 2015 - Dec 2018

I was responsible for managing, teams, processes, policies, KPIs, pricing strategy, inventory, contracts, and registrations. I also managed IT projects with an emphasis on the business model in SAP ERP.

Education

2022 - 2023

Technical Course

Full Stack development

Digital College

Web programming concepts and fundamentals, programming logic and algorithms, Git and Github. Frontend in Javascript, HTML, CCS and React. Backend development in Node.js, Express.js and MySQL. System operation with DevOps, Cloud Infrastructure, and deployment.

2019 - 2020

Master's Degree

Master of Operation Management Porto Business School - University of Porto

Analyze, design, and implement production systems aimed at maximizing value and ensuring they are aligned with the organization's strategy.

2013 - 2018

Bachelor's Degree

Bachelor of Production Engineer University of Fortaleza

Design, implement, improve and maintain production systems with a systemic approach in order to deal with integrated systems, equipment, technologies, and products.